Guide to the Lutheran Campus Ministry Records, 1946-1997 UA.31.04.0012
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Lutheran Campus Ministry records
1946-1997
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Lutheran Student Center (Lutheran Campus Ministry)
UA.31.04.0012
7 Linear Feet
The Lutheran Campus Ministry serves Lutheran students at Duke and North Carolina Central University. The collection contains materials related to the operations of the organization dating back to 1946.
Provenance
The Lutheran Campus Ministry Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a transfer in April, 2000.
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
Historical note
A Lutheran Student Association was organized on campus in 1925 with 14 students. The present Lutheran Campus Ministry serves students at Duke and North Carolina Central University. It is supported by the Lutheran Campus Ministry Council of Durham, NC which is affiliated with the Evangelical Lutheran Church of America and the Lutheran Church - Missouri Synod.
Collection Overview
The collection contains minutes, correspondence, memoranda, reports, brochures, newsletters, flyers, reference files, financial records, rosters, and other records generated in the operations of the Lutheran Campus Ministry, its predecessor organizations, and the religious life staff at both Duke University and North Carolina Central University.
College students -- Religious life; Duke University -- Students -- Religious activities; North Carolina Central University -- Students -- Religious Life; Lutheran Church -- Missouri Synod; Evangelical Lutheran Church in America; Duke University. Lutheran Student Center (Lutheran Campus Ministry)
- Lutheran Campus Ministry, 1946-1997; 1
  - Freshman Packets, Devotionals, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Stations of the Cross, 1986-1992 (Box 1)
  - Contemporary Easter Vigil, In Use, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Easter Vigil Services, 1966 and undated (Box 1)
  - An Easter Vigil as Celebrated at Duke Chapel, 1980-1987 (Box 1)
  - Table Eucharist (Could be adapted for Agape Meal), Undated (Box 1)
  - LBW Evening Service of Light with Communion, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Ceremony of Blessing the Animals, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Coffee House Ministry, 1965-1968 (Box 1)
  - Services of Installation, 1977-1984 (Box 1)
  - Installation Exec Council, Undated (Box 1)
  - Lutheran Student Movement, Southwest Region, 1977-1984 (Box 1)
  - National and Regional Lutheran Student Movement, 1948-1968 (Box 1)
  - 1989 Minutes, 1987-1991 (Box 1)
  - Fund-raising, 1980-1984 (Box 1)
  - Episcopal/Lutheran, 1972 (Box 1)
  - NLCM Involvement at Duke, 1984-1985 (Box 1)
  - Duke University Financial Arrangements, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Faith, Science, Future Conference Duke University, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Campus Ministry Brochure, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Campus Ministry Review, 1988 (Box 1)
  - "What Men Live By," Leo Tolstoy, Undated (Box 1)
  - Goals from Retreat, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Campus Ministry By-Laws, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Goals, Board Sub-committee, 1984-1989 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
  - Budget Proposals, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Judicatory Allotments, 1988-1991 (Box 1)
  - Campus Pastor/Students Sub-committee, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
  - Ash Wednesday at Duke through the Years, 1976-1996 (Box 1)
  - Duke Passover Haggadah, 1979-1987 (Box 1)
  - Minutes and Staff, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - NC Synod ECLA Campus Ministry, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
  - NC Synod ECLA Campus Ministry, 1990-1992 (Box 1)
  - NC Synod ECLA Campus Ministry, 1991-1992 (Box 1)
  - NC Synod ECLA Campus Ministry, 1990 (Box 1)
  - NC Synod ECLA Campus Ministry, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Contacts, Things to Do, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
  - Council Minutes, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Minutes and Memoranda, 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - Ministry Board, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Council of Durham Minutes, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - Introductory Brochures, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Durham Ad Hoc Committee, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Durham Ad Hoc Committee, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Durham Ad Hoc Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - Durham Ad Hoc Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - Durham Ad Hoc Committee, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Durham Ad Hoc Committee, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
  - Durham Ad Hoc Committee, 1980-1982 (Box 2)
  - Agency Budget Planning Forms, 1979-1982 (Box 2)
  - Board Member's Notebook, 1981-1985 (Box 2)
  - Durham Campus Ministry (Miscellaneous), 1987-1988 (Box 2)
  - Durham Campus Ministry (Miscellaneous), 1986-1987 (Box 2)
  - Council of Durham, Minutes, Memoranda, Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
  - Bylaws, 1988 January (Box 2)
  - Postal Records, 1992-1993 (Box 2)
  - Reports, Documents, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
  - Pamphlets and Documents, 1990-1992 (Box 2)
  - Proposals, Funds, Documents, 1989-1990 (Box 2)
  - Minutes, Documents, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
  - Minutes, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Minutes, Memoranda, 1986-1990 (Box 2)
  - "Goals" from Review Team, 1991 (Box 2)
  - NC Synod ECLA Campus Ministry Committee, 1994 (Box 2)
  - NC Synod ECLA Campus Ministry, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Annual Report, 1944-1946 (Box 2)
  - Annual Report, 1946-1947 (Box 2)
  - Pamphlets, Annual Report, 1947-1948 (Box 2)
  - Annual Report, 1948-1949 (Box 2)
  - Constitution, Annual Report, 1949-1950 (Box 2)
  - Annual Report, Weekly Reports, 1950-1951 (Box 2)
  - Reports, Memoranda, 1951-1952 (Box 2)
  - Report, Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 2)
  - Constitution, Minutes, 1953-1954 (Box 2)
  - Annual Report, 1954-1955 (Box 2)
  - Annual Report, 1955-1956 (Box 2)
  - Postcard Survey, 1956-1957 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, Reports, Pamphlets, 1957-1958 (Box 2)
  - Schedule, Budget, 1958-1959 (Box 2)
  - Service of Worship, 1959-1960 (Box 2)
  - Statements, Pamphlets, 1960-1961 (Box 2)
  - Durham, 1962-1963 (Box 2)
  - Durham, 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Campus Ministry Reports, 1962-1968 (Box 2)
  - Durham, 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - Durham, 1964-1965 (Box 2)
  - Durham, 1966-1967 (Box 2)
  - Durham, 1965-1966 (Box 2)
  - Durham, 1967-1968 (Box 2)
  - Durham, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
  - Durham, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Durham, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Durham, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Durham, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
  - Durham, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Durham, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
  - Records, 1949-1956 (Box 3)
  - Durham, Undated (Box 3)
  - Lutheran Students at Duke, Undated and 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Mailing Lists from Previous Years, 1984-1986 (Box 3)
  - Students from the Late 1980s-1990s, 1986-1988 (Box 3)
  - A History of Efforts Leading to By-Laws Governing LCMD Culminating with 1980 Bylaws, 1980-1984 (Box 3)
  - Camps and Retreat Centers, 1980-1981 (Box 3)
  - United Christian Campus Ministry Office, 1996 (Box 3)
  - United Christian Campus Ministry, 1995 (Box 3)
  - United Christian Campus Ministry, 1994 (Box 3)
  - United Christian Campus Ministry, 1993 (Box 3)
  - United Christian Campus Ministry, 1992 (Box 3)
  - United Christian Campus Ministry, 1990-1991 (Box 3)
  - NCCU United Christian Campus Ministry, 1988-1989 (Box 3)
  - NCCU United Christian Campus Ministry, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Inter-Section Newsletter, 1980-1981 (Box 3)
  - Inter-Section Newsletter, 1981-1982 (Box 3)
  - Inter-Section Newsletter, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Inter-Section Newsletter, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
  - Viva Newsletter, 1984-1985 (Box 3)
  - Viva Newsletter, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Viva Newsletter, 1986-1987 (Box 3)
  - Viva Newsletter, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Viva Newsletter, 1988-1989 (Box 3)
  - Viva Newsletter, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
  - Viva Newsletter, 1990-1991 (Box 3)
  - Viva Newsletter, 1991-1992 (Box 3)
  - Viva Newsletter, 1992-1993 (Box 3)
  - Facilities and Building Communications and Other Communications, Undated (Box 3)
  - Viva Newsletter, 1995-1996 (Box 3)
  - Viva Newsletter and Other Communication Pieces, 1993-1994 (Box 3)
  - Resources, 1994-1995 (Box 3)
  - Running Account of 1) Ads Placed at Duke 2) Payments for Ads, 1986-1997 (Box 3)
  - Running Account of 1) Ads Placed at Duke 2) Payments for Ads, 1986-1987 (Box 3)
  - Old Ads for Christmas Carols, 1969-1996 (Box 3)
  - Mailing List Publications, 1993-1995 (Box 3)
  - Ministry/Religion Students, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Faculty/Staff Lists, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Campus Ministry Council Mailing Lists, 1995-1996 (Box 3)
  - Steering Committee, 1995-1996 (Box 3)
  - Steering Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 3)
  - A Service of Parting, Undated (Box 3)
  - Student Directing Committee, 1951-1964 (Box 4)
  - Student Directing Committee, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Articles of Incorporation, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Student Center Study, 1962-1963 (Box 4)
  - Student Directing Committee Minutes, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Student Directing Committee Minutes, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Student Directing Committee Minutes, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Student Directing Committee Minutes, 1968 (Box 4)
  - Student Directing Committee, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Board of Directors Minutes, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Board of Directors Minutes, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Board of Directors Minutes, 1972 (Box 4)
  - Board of Directors Minutes, 1973 (Box 4)
  - Board of Directors Minutes, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Lutheran Campus Council Minutes, 1985 (Box 4)
  - LCMD Records, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Campus Ministry Board Minutes, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Records, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Records, Minutes, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Records, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Minutes, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Inter-Section Newsletter, 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - Inter-Section Newsletter, 1978-1979 (Box 4)
  - Inter-Section Newsletter, 1977-1978 (Box 4)
  - Material for Brochure, Undated (Box 4)
  - Duke University, General, 1964-1981 (Box 4)
  - Faculty Group, 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - Duke Faculty/Staff Gatherings, 1988-1996 (Box 4)
  - Duke Faculty/Staff Gatherings, 1986-1988 (Box 4)
  - Grad Students, 1984-1988 (Box 4)
  - Religious Life Staff, 1994-1995 (Box 4)
  - Duke Campus Ministry Staff, 1993-1994 (Box 4)
  - Duke Campus Ministry Staff, 1992-1993 (Box 4)
  - Duke Campus Ministry Staff, 1991-1992 (Box 4)
  - Duke Campus Ministry Staff, 1990-1991 (Box 4)
  - Duke Campus Ministry, 1989-1990 (Box 4)
  - Duke Campus Ministry, 1988-1989 (Box 4)
  - Duke Campus Ministry, 1987-1988 (Box 4)
  - Duke Campus Ministry, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
  - Duke Campus Ministry, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Duke Campus Ministry, 1984-1985 (Box 5)
  - Duke Campus Ministry, 1982-1984 (Box 5)
  - Study in Homosexuality, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Study in Homosexuality, 1976-1984 (Box 5)
  - Social Statements Newsletter, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Social Statements Newsletter, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Studies and Papers, 1959-1986 (Box 5)
  - Studies and Papers, 1976-1981 (Box 5)
  - Committee, 1976-1978 (Box 5)
  - NCCU Campus Ministry, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
  - NCCU United Campus Ministry, 1983-1986 (Box 5)
  - NCCU United Campus Ministry, 1964-1983 (Box 5)
  - NCCU, 1981-1995 (Box 5)
  - Student Residential Assistants, 1990-1994 (Box 5)
  - NCCU, 1983-1993 (Box 5)
  - On Wings Like Eagles Newsletter, 1994-1995 (Box 5)
  - On Wings Like Eagles Newsletter, 1992-1993 (Box 5)
  - On Wings Like Eagles Newsletter, 1991-1992 (Box 5)
  - On Wings Like Eagles Newsletter, 1990-1991 (Box 5)
  - Review Process, Undated (Box 5)
  - Freshman Letters, 1963-1987 (Box 5)
  - Duke Correspondence, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Lutheran Student Movement, Regional, 1976-1992 (Box 5)
  - LSF, Missouri Synod Group, 1960-1961 (Box 5)
  - Duke Chapel Policy, Statement on Same-Sex Marriages, Undated (Box 5)
  - Duke University Harassment Policy, 1993 November (Box 6)
  - Policies of Duke University, 1992-1995 (Box 6)
  - Alcohol Control Group, 1993-1994 (Box 6)
  - Rape, Sexual Assault, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Peer Ministry, 1994-1995 (Box 6)
  - Peer Ministry Possibilities, 1993-1994 (Box 6)
  - Peer Ministry Records, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Peer Ministry, 1993-1994 (Box 6)
  - John: Fund Raising, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Associate Ministry, 1995-1996 (Box 6)
  - Installation Service for Associate (Peer) Ministry, Undated (Box 6)
  - Religious Life Staff, 1995-1996 (Box 6)
  - Student Religious Activities, 1993-1996 (Box 6)
  - Chapel Policies, 1993-1995 (Box 6)
  - Release Forms for Trips, 1990-1994 (Box 6)
  - Planning for Next Year (General), 1994 (Box 6)
  - MLK Program, 1996 (Box 6)
  - By-Laws of LCMD as Revised 5/23/91, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Lutheran Campus Ministry of Durham (LCMD), 1993 (Box 6)
  - Records, 1980-1985 (Box 6)
  - The Lutheran Blue Devil Newsletter, 1956 December (Box 6)
  - Council Meeting Records, 1995-1996 (Box 6)
  - Viva Newsletter, 1988-1992 (Box 7)
  - Council Meeting Records, 1995-1996 (Box 7)
  - Council Meeting Records, 1995-1996 (Box 7)